死而
死而复生
(墨西哥城)
(亡灵节)
我说你是不是快等不及了
你去哪儿？
Where are you going?
去去就来
I won't be long.
欢迎 亲爱的斯奇亚拉先生
Welcome, Signor Sciarra.
旅途还愉快吗？
I trust you had a pleasant journey.
带来了吗？
Do you have it?
带来了 在那儿呢
Yes. It's over there.
什么时候炸体育馆？
When do we blow the stadium?
下午六点钟
This evening at six.
那么离开所乘的飞机呢？
And the flight out of here?
全都安排好了
All arranged.
之后有什么安排？
And then what?
之后啊 我就去拜访 幽冥国王
Then I visit The Pale King.
来干一杯 我的朋友
A toast, my friend.
敬亡灵
To Death!
那我先干为敬
Bottoms up.
在广场碰头
Meet me in the square!
《007系列之幽灵党》
(墨西哥惨剧)
想从哪儿就从哪说起
Start anywhere you like.
你慢慢说 007 不过五分钟后
Take your time, 007, but in five minutes
联合安全局的头儿
the head of the Joint Security Service
会从那扇门走进来
is going to walk through that door,
而我得向他解释
and I've got to explain to him
为什么我们的特工会一时兴起 独自去墨西哥晃悠
how one of our agents decided to potter off to Mexico, all on his own,
然后引发这场国际性事件
and cause an international incident.
但无论怎么说 没有我们情况会更糟
With all due respect, sir, it could've been worse.
还不够糟？你把半条街炸飞了
Worse? You blew up half a bloody block.
半条街总比牺牲一体育馆的人强吧？
Well, better half a block than a whole stadium full of people.
那时你可没拍板的权力
You had no authority.
没有
None.
你也知道 我们正经历
As you know, we're in the middle of the biggest shakeup
英国情报系统最大规模的改组
in the history of British intelligence.
我们跟军情五处合并的文件还墨迹未干
The ink's barely dry on this merger with Ml5...
五处就盼着找个机会
and already they're itching for a chance to scrap
永远拿掉00项目
the double-0 program forever.
而你刚好成全了他们
And you've just given them one.
你说的没错
You're right, sir.
今天你的日子不会好过
You have got a tricky day ahead.
我现在是在严肃的问你
This is an official question.
那天在墨西哥城 你到底干什么去了？
Mexico City. What were you doing there?
我只是碰巧在度假 早该休的假正好想休了
It was just a coincidence. I was taking some overdue holiday.
那好 行吧
Okay. Fine.
从今天早上开始你被正式限制行动
As of this morning, you are officially grounded.
我决定无限期中止你所有的行动
I'm standing you down from all operations indefinitely.
很好啊 长官
Very good, sir.
007？
007?
您请讲
Sir?
我不管你在玩什么小把戏
I don't know what you're playing at,
最好马上收手
but whatever it is, it has to stop.
马上
Now.
- 真对不住 打扰你们了吧？- 哪有？
- So sorry. Am I interrupting? - Not remotely.
007 这位是麦克斯·登比
007, I'd like you to meet Max Denbigh,
联合安全局的一把手
head of the Joint Security Service.
终于见到007真身了 听说了不少事迹
It's a pleasure to finally meet you, 007. I've heard a lot about you.
大部分是好事
Most of it good.
祝贺你新官走马上任
Congratulations on your new appointment.
谢谢了
Thank you.
现在能叫你C先生了吧？
I suppose we should call you C now.
不 叫我麦克斯就行了
No, no. "Max," please.
我还是叫你C好了 C
No, I think I'll call you C,
C
C...
随你便了
As you wish.
我们的门永远敞开 007 随时欢迎我的下属
Well, my door is always open, 007, for my employees.
这次合并掀开了新篇章
This merger's gonna be a whole new chapter for us.
我们要带领英国情报系统走出黑暗时代
We're going to bring British intelligence out of the Dark Ages
重见天日
into the light.
听起来相当不错
That all sounds lovely.
就这样 007 明天向Q报到体检 谢谢
That'll be all, 007. Report to Q tomorrow for medical, thank you.
好的 长官
Very good, sir.
詹姆斯
James?
莫尼彭尼
Moneypenny...
我说 会开得怎么样？
So? How was the meeting?
挺好的 谢谢
Very good, thank you.
给你
Here.
法医终于把这个解禁了 这是什么？
Forensics finally released this. What is it?
是从天幕庄园抢救出的私人物品
It's personal effects they recovered from Skyfall.
太好了 待会儿再给我捎来吧
Perfect. You can bring it to me later.
- 你什么意思？- 9点钟送到我家来
- What do you mean? - My place, 9:00.
晚上好
Evening.
请进
Come in.
你才搬进来吗？
Have you just moved in?
不是啊
No.
你这套布置我挺喜欢
Well, I like what you've clone with the place.
你的档案
Your delivery.
谢谢
Thank you.
要不要喝一杯？
Would you like a drink?
算了我有不过夜
No, thanks. I'm not staying.
那可惜了
That's a shame.
怎么回事 詹姆斯？
What's going on, James?
现在军情六处没有人不在讨论这事儿
There's not one person at Ml6 who isn't talking about it.
他们在讨论什么事啊 你说说
Talking about what, exactly?
他们说你在墨西哥这次做的过火了
That what you did in Mexico was one step too far.
还说你玩完了
That you're finished.
你怎么看？
And what do you think?
我恰恰觉得你好戏才开场
I think you'rejust getting started.
我不明白你的意思
I don't know what you mean.
好吧
All right.
我猜你手头有个秘密
I think you've got a secret.
而且你跟谁都不想说
And it's something you won't tell anyone.
因为你谁都不相信
Because you don't trust anyone.
我若有什么不测 007 我需要你做件事
If anything happens to me, 007, I need you to do something.
找一个男的 他叫叫马科·斯奇亚拉
Find a man called Marco Sciarra.
干掉他
Kill him.
然后别错过他的葬礼
And don't miss the funeral.
我的老天
Jesus.
你从哪儿弄到的？
Where did you get it?
她刚死就发到了我的邮箱
In my mailbox just after she died.
她总能出乎人意料
Well, she was never short of surprises.
即便是死亡也阻挡不了她的工作
She wasn't gonna let death get in the way of herjob.
而我也开始跟踪斯奇亚拉
I've been tracking Sciarra ever since.
那你查到什么了？
And what have you found?
还没有什么重大发现
Nothing significant yet.
他葬礼是哪天？
When's the funeral?
三天之后 在罗马举行
Three days. In Rome.
你要是指望M会批准你去 那你真是疯了
If you think M's signing off on that, you're insane.
他不会让你离开半步的
He won't let you out of his sight.
是的 这也算是个小麻烦
Yes, it's a bit of a problem.
听我说
Listen.
能不能暗地里帮我挖挖情报去？
Could you do a little quiet digging for me?
我在墨西哥听到一个名字 冥王
I heard a name in Mexico. "The Pale King."
你要我给你当卧底吗？
You want me to be your mole.
没错
Yes.
你凭什么认为我值得信任？
And what makes you think you can trust me?
直觉
Instinct.
(临时监护令)
可怜的老楼 已经计划被拆除了
Poor old girl. Rigged for demolition in a week.
拆了比修复重建
Cheaper to knock her down than to rebuild.
要省钱
Still.
光阴脚步匆匆 谁都不等
Time waits for no man and all that.
对了 钱都花到这上面来了
Anyway, all the money's been spent on this,
国家安全中心的新大楼
the New Centre for National Security.
这不就是C的新巢穴嘛？
So that's C's new digs.
你见过他了吗？
You've met him, have you?
昨天见过 这人什么来头？
Yesterday. What do we know about him?
典型的中央政府高级官僚
Classic Whitehall mandarin.
去年写了份材料
Wrote a dossier last year
说00项目已经过时了
on how the double-0 program was obsolete,
说无人机可以代劳海外那些龌龊活儿
how drones could do all our dirty work abroad.
他跟内政大臣还是同学
Went to school with the Home Secretary.
果不其然
Of course, he did.
这次合并只是开了个头
This merger's just the start of it.
三天后在东京有个会议
In three days, there's a security conference in Tokyo
将决定新的世界秩序
to decide the New World Order.
若能说动各方 他就有权无限制地获取
If C gets his way, he'll have unlimited access
9个国家的情报
to the combined intelligence streams of nine countries.
当然也包括我们
Including us.
不错
Quite.
你不在的时候发生了许多事
Well, a lot's happened while you were away.
汉堡发生列车爆炸 突尼斯发生工厂爆炸
A train bombing in Hamburg and an industrial explosion in Tunisia.
现在这时机对我们不利
It's not great timing for us.
全是在帮C的忙啊
It's all rather playing into C's hands.
而M 我猜他也感受到压力了
M, well, let's say he's feeling the pressure.
对 我发现了
Yeah, I've noticed.
这边来 007
Now, this way, 007.
留神啊 脚底有点滑滑
Be careful. It's a trifle slippery.
合并之后 Q在高官们面前
Q wasn't exactly feeling at home in Whitehall,
觉得不太自在
what with the new merger,
所以在这儿另行开张 躲开那些烦人的眼线
so he set up shop here, away from prying eyes, as it were.
听说他为你设计了特别的东西
I hear he's got something rather special planned for you.
我都迫不及待了
I can hardly wait.
啊 007
Ah, 007
- 你好 Q - 抱歉 我这里太乱
- Q. - Please excuse the mess.
一切都还在变
Everything's a little bit up in the air,
还没尘埃落定呢
what with the changes and all.
有几样东西要给你看
Couple of things to get through.
咱们先干正事吧
Shall we get started?
放松就好
Just relax.
对 就这样
That's it. Lovely.
现在你会觉得有些
Now, you may feel a small...
老天爷啊
Christ!
刺痛感
...prick.
这是什么？
What is it?
最前沿的纳米技术
Cutting-edge nanotechnology.
智能血液
Smart Blood.
是血管里的微型芯片
Microchips in your bloodstream.
可以帮我们定位你在外的活动
Allows us to track your movements in the field.
看到这些读数了吗？
You see those readouts?
在地球任何角落都能测到你的生命体征
We can monitor your vital signs from anywhere on the planet.
这个实在太棒了
Well, that sounds marvelous.
算是墨西哥事件后的保险措施
Call it a post-Mexico insurance policy.
M直接指示要搞的
By direct order of M.
这我完全能理解
I completely understand.
很好
Good.
好吧 我这里还有 还有最后一样东西
Right. Well, l'vejust, um, got one last thing for you
你看完就能走了
and you can be on your way.
不是一般的气派吧？
Magnificent, isn't she?
起步加速到60迈只需3.2秒
Zero to 60 in three point two seconds.
全车身防弹 还深藏各种绝技
Fully bulletproof. A few little tricks up her sleeve.
只可惜她本来是你的 但现在
It's a shame, really. She was meant for you,
她配给009使用了
but she's been reassigned to 009.
不过这个你可以有
But you can have this.
能派上大用场吗？
Does it do anything?
会报时是肯定的
It tells the time.
能帮你变得更加守时
Might help with your punctuality issues.
- M的主意吧？- 你猜对了
- M's idea? - Precisely.
要提醒你一句 这表的闹铃动静相当大
Oh, one word of warning. The alarm is rather loud.
你应该懂我的意思
If you know what I mean.
我想是的
I think I do.
对了 这个老家伙得花不少时间呢
Oh, yes. That old thing is taking quite a bit of time.
它大部分已经没法用了
Mind you, there wasn't much left to work on.
就方向盘还好使
Only a steering wheel.
我记得告诉过你要带回一整台车 不是带回一台车架
I believe I said, "Bring it back in one piece," not, "Bring back one piece."
那好吧 好好享受假期吧 007
Anyway, enjoy your downtime, 007.
- Q - 怎么了？
- Q. - Yes?
既然你现在能对我的所有行踪都了如指掌
Well, now you know exactly where I am all of the time.
那能不能帮我个忙？
Will you do something for me?
你脑子里在想什么呢？
What do you have in mind, exactly?
能帮我消失吗？
Make me disappear.
唔 我提醒你一下 我现在直接对M负责
May I remind you that I answer directly to M.
我有一套按揭要还 还养了两只猫
I also have a mortgage. And two cats to feed.
哦 所以我建议你最好先相信我
Well, then I suggest you trust me,
哪怕是为了那两只猫呢
for the sake of the cats.
很高兴见到你 007 真的
Well, it's lovely to see you, 007. Lovely.
我要提醒你
Um, now, I meant to tell you,
目前这个智能血液 它显然还处于开发阶段
the Smart Blood program is obviously still in its developmental phase.
所以我们也会偶尔遇到 头24小时接收不到信号的情况
So we may experience the odd drop in coverage during the first 24 hours...
其实48小时内 即便部署了也会有失灵
48 hours after administration,
在那之后就没问题了
but after that it should work perfectly.
我会给你寄明信片的
I'll send you a postcard.
求你别这样
Please, don't.
(谢谢你 詹姆斯)
早上好 那是什么？
Morning.
一个追求者送的礼物而已
What's that? Oh, it'sjust something from an admirer.
今天不是你生日吧？
It's not your birthday, is it?
不是 长官
No, sir.
人家上周才过生日
That was last week.
早啊
Morning.
009已经到了 要来提那辆DB10跑车 他在楼上等你呢
009 has arrived to pick up the DB10, sir. He's waiting upstairs.
好的 行 先这样
Oh, good. Yes, fine.
这下子好了
Oh, shit.
(罗马)
还请夫人节哀顺变
I'm sorry for your loss.
你认识我丈夫吗？
You knew my husband?
只简单打过照面
All too briefly.
你是做什么的？
What do you do?
人寿保险
Life insurance.
可惜你来的有点晚
A little late for that.
对于您丈夫是晚了
For your husband, yes.
不过对您来说呢
But what about you?
对我？
Me?
我听说一些寡妇在失去丈夫之后不久就会意外丧命
I hear the life expectancy of some widows can be very short.
你怎么可以这么说你？
How can you talk like this?
没看见我还在悲伤中吗？
Can't you see I'm grieving?
没有
No.
多美妙的景致啊
What a lovely view.
你这是在浪费时间
You're wasting your time.
还有一百多人会追杀我的
There are 100 more that will come after me.
你这只是帮我 活五分钟而已
All you buy me is five minutes.
真是难得
Excellent
该来喝一杯了
Time fora drink.
是你杀了他
You killed him,
没说错吧？
didn't you?
你杀了我丈夫
My husband.
他本身就是杀手
He was an assassin.
相信我 他不会觉得我是私事公办
Trust me, he won't take it personally.
你这是亲手送我上断头台 我以前地位很高的
You signed my death warrant. I was respected.
你在忠于一个你恨的人
Loyal to a man you hated.
他欣赏我的沉默
He trusted my silence.
现在他走了 我也玩完了
With him gone, I'm a dead woman.
我谁都不会相信
I can trust nobody.
我很了解这种感受
I know the feeling well.
那我就告诉你 我不信任你
Well, I can tell you that I don't trust you.
你的直觉相当的准
Well, then you have impeccable instincts.
你要是不马上离开 我们就没命了
If you don't leave now, we'll die together.
这可比别的死法痛快多了
I can think of worse ways to go.
我看你简直是是疯了 你叫什么？
Then you're obviously crazy, Mister...
邦德
Bond.
詹姆斯·邦德
James Bond.
我说的那些人啊
These people,
你可不知道他们的做派
if you just knew what they could do.
他们能耐非常大
The power they have.
你丈夫有没有提及过 冥王
Did your husband ever mention "The Pale King?"
没有
No.
那个神秘的组织
The organization,
成员几乎很少见面
they hardly ever meet.
但由于我丈夫出了那么大的事
Butbecause of what happened to my husband,
他们今晚要开会
they meet tonight.
为什么？
Why?
要挑选出替补的人
To choose a replacement.
在哪儿？
Where?
在卡登撒华彩宫
The Palazzo Cardenza.
午夜时分 估计很有看头
Midnight. Sounds like fun.
我没准会去看看
I might drop by.
他整个人都陷进去了
He was obsessed.
他耗在那里的时间比陪我的都要多
He spent more time with them than with me.
那这个男的可真不聪明
Then the man was a fool.
不留个电话号码？
Leaving your number?
我找了一个美国朋友 叫费利克斯
I've called an American friend of mine. Felix.
他会联系美国大使馆带你离开的
He'll contact his embassy and get you out of here.
保证你的安全
You'll be safe.
詹姆斯 别走
Don't go, James.
你不能去那儿
If you go there,
那可是个杀人不眨眼的地方
you're crossing over to a place where there is no mercy.
我必须得走
I have to go.
祝你好运 亲爱的露西亚
嘿 要上哪儿去啊？
还不亮明身份 你这混蛋
你是谁啊？
我是米老鼠呀 你是谁？
请进吧
在线购药网站提供了
Pharmacy sites has provided...
很好的新销售平台
an excellent new sales platform.
我们将许多网站改造成未批准药物的交易场所
We have adapted many of them into clearinghouses for unapproved drugs.
除此之外
In addition to which,
最新的数据显示 我们已控制了
the latest figures show that we presently control
70%的抗疟疾疫苗
70% of antimalarial vaccines,
34%的艾滋病药物和40%肿瘤药物
34% of H.I.V., and 40% of all oncological drugs
在撒哈拉以南的市场
across Sub-Saharan Africa.
但是 世界卫生组织真是跟我们过不去
But we face challenges from the WHO
他们正在打击我们所谓的仿冒药品
in their campaign against our counterfeit pharmaceuticals.
我们已经锁定需要处理的关键人物
We have now identified the key individuals to target.
希望能像人口贩卖委员会那次一样成功
We expect the same success as we had against the Council on Human Trafficking.
沃格尔博士
Dr. Vogel
在委员会全体请辞后
Since the board's resignation...
我们已将16万女移民安排进休闲性产业
...we have placed 160,000 migrated females into the leisure sector.
而接近完成的 九只眼 全球监控倡议
The impending completion of the Global Surveillance initiative...
意味着我们将拥有独一无二的监视能力
...will mean our capability is second to none...
而现在到了该强势扩张的时候了
...and now is the moment for aggressive expansion.
这绝对是个好消息
The news is only good...
别让我打断你们了
Don't let me interrupt you.
这绝对是个好消息
The news is only good...
我们得到增强的监控能力
Our increased surveillance capability...
意味着来自政府情报机构的阻力
...means government intelligence agencies...
将被轻而易举化解
...are easily counteracted.
我们赢定了
We are winning.
谢谢你 博士
Thank you, Doctor.
现在来处理手头上的事项
Now, on to the matter at hand.
在我们成功实施汉堡和突尼斯的袭击之后
After the success of our attacks in Hamburg and Tunisia,
在墨西哥城的袭击被迫中止
the aborted attack in Mexico City
而我们杰出的的同事马科·斯奇亚拉不幸身亡
and the death of our valued colleague, Marco Sciarra,
他身后留下了一项未完成的使命
leaves one of his duties outstanding.
格拉先生 冥王 必须被处理掉
Signor Guerra, The Pale King must be terminated.
你可否去趟奥尔陶斯？
Will you make the journey to Altaussee?
当然可以
Of course.
我是绝对忠于组织的
My loyalty to this organization is total.
我这份忠诚至死不渝
I will protect it with my last breath.
绝不会再有
There will be no more...
业余之举
...amateurs.
绝不会再示弱
No more shows of weakness.
在座有没有哪位反对格拉先生接任这个席位？
Does anyone challenge Signor Guerra for this position?
欢迎你
Welcome.
请陈述你能接任斯奇亚拉的理由
State your credentials for succeeding Signor Sciarra.
真有意思
BLOFELDI It's funny.
墨西哥那次宛如钟声勾起了我遥远的记忆
All that excitement in Mexico City rang a distant bell.
而现在
And now,
就在今晚一刹那间 我突然就全明白了
suddenly, this evening, it makes perfect sense.
欢迎你 詹姆斯
Welcome, James.
真是好久不见了
It's been a long time.
但我们最终还是再会了
But, finally, here we are.
你怎么才来？
What took you so long?
布 谷
Cuckoo.
再见了 米老鼠
Ciao, Mickey Mouse.
这不是跟我闹着玩儿吗
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
不会吧
No.
脑子有病啊
呼叫莫尼彭尼
Moneypenny...
邦德？
Bond?
听着 莫尼彭尼 汉堡 突尼斯
Listen, Moneypenny. Hamburg, Tunisia,
和墨西哥袭击是相互关联的
Mexico City, they're all linked.
是同一个组织策划的连环袭击
It's one organization coordinating multiple attacks.
看来她说的没错
So, she was right.
她就没错过
Of course, she was.
- 我查过了 - 谁打来的？
- I ran that check. - Who is it?
是我老板 他信用卡被偷了
Oh, my boss had his credit card stolen.
不是大事 你赶紧先睡去吧
It's nothing. Why don't you go back to sleep.
别弄太久啊
Don't be long.
- 谁在那儿？- 没谁啊
- Who was that? - No one.
你没说实话
No, it wasn't.
就一普通朋友
It's just a friend.
大半夜还在你那儿？
At this time of night?
生活就是这样 詹姆斯 有时你也该体验下
It's called life, James. You should try it sometime.
那个 幽冥国王 貌似是位你曾经交过手的人
The Pale King. It looks like you've had dealings with him before.
- 量子危机那次 - 果不其然
- Quantum. - Of course.
是怀特先生 就是他
Mr. White! That's him.
最近一次现身 是在奥地利的奥尔陶斯 四个月前的事了
Last unconfirmed sighting, Altaussee in Austria, four months ago.
你先等一下
Hold that thought.
- 还没挂吧？- 没挂
- You still there? - Yeah.
我再报个名字 行吗？
Run another name, will you?
可以 说吧
Okay. Go.
是个男的 叫弗朗兹·奥伯豪斯
A man called Franz Oberhauser. He's...
查查他生前和死后的档案和行踪
And check his files before and after his death.
怎么还有死后 什么意思？
After his death? What are you talking about?
拜托 你照办就是了
Please, just do it.
好的 Q 给我亮亮家伙
Okay, Q, give me something.
真是越来越给劲了
That's more like it.
试试手气吧
Here goes nothing.
晚上好
Good evening.
不要听信他们减少监控的主张
Do not let them tell you we need less surveillance.
相反要增加更多 更加多
We need more. Much more.
我愿重申 这个九只眼委员会将有权获得
I say again, the Nine Eyes committee would have full access
所有成员国的情报信息流
to the combined intelligence streams of all member states.
数据越多分析得越透彻
More data, more analysis,
发生恐怖袭击的可能性就会越低
less likelihood of a terrorist attack.
女士们 先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
到了全世界安全机构联合起来的时候了
it's time for the security services of the world to unite.
各自为战 我们不堪一击
Alone, we are weak.
联合起来 我们汇聚全球力量
Together, we're a global power.
这肯定不走选举程序
An unelected one.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
谢谢
现在就方案进行表决
We will now vote on the resolution.
女士们先生们 请开始投票
Ladies and gentlemen, please cast your vote.
结果是八票赞成一票反对
The vote is eight to one in favor.
但是如各位所知
However, as you know,
只有全票赞成才能通过决议
we cannot proceed unless by unanimous vote.
因此 九只眼议案未能获得通过
The Nine Eyes motion is therefore not passed.
这就是民主啊
Democracy.
感谢女士们先生们
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen.
今晚的会议现在休会
This evening's session is adjourned.
(我们能否确定邦德就在伦敦？)
长官您好
Yes, sir.
拜托请告诉我007就在伦敦
Please, tell me 007 is in London.
是的
Oh, yes.
我那个 现在先让我看一下
Um, I'll just take a look now, sir.
因为他要是不在 你丫麻烦就大了
Because if he isn't, you're in deep shit.
我TM就给你10秒钟时间
You've got precisely 10 seconds.
找到了 长官 他应该是在切尔西
I have him, sir. He appears to be in Chelsea.
给我盯死了 等我回来 明白吗？
Well, lwant eyes on him when I get back, understood?
我完全明白您的意思
I completely understand,
长官
sir.
帮我个忙行吗？下手要快点儿
Do me a favor. Make it quick.
到楼上来 怀特先生
Upstairs, Mr. White.
我知道死神会以一张熟悉的面孔前来索命
I always knew death would wear a familiar face,
但没想到会是你
but not yours.
我为何会有此等荣幸啊 邦德先生？
To what do I owe this pleasure, Mr. Bond?
最近我参加了一场会议
I was at a meeting recently
然后出现了你的名字
and your name came Up.
很荣幸伦敦方面还在讨论我
I'm flattered London is still talking about me.
那不是军情六处的会
It wasn't MI6.
是在罗马开的
It was Rome.
是你的组织 不是我的
Yourteam, not mine.
上个月 我在手机里发现了剧毒的金属铊
Last month, I found thallium in my cell phone.
他真是不辱使命 我就剩几个星期了 没准还短点
It's done its job. I have a few weeks. Maybe less.
所以说真是缘分啊 邦德先生
So, here we are, Mr. Bond,
两个将死之人一起共度良宵
two dead men enjoying the evening.
你到底干了什么？
What did you do?
我没有听他的命令
I disobeyed him.
我曾竭尽全力追随他
I followed him as far as I could.
可是他变了
He changed.
我明白了
Oh, I see.
你良心发现了
You grew a conscience.
咱们恩怨归恩怨 可这样
Our game is our game. But this?
干扯上女人 扯上儿童
Women, children...
这金属铊起码说明
Well, the thallium would suggest
他不再欣赏你了
that he doesn't like you very much anymore.
而且你看他也是一样的
And clearly the feeling is mutual.
你还不如告诉我该怎样找到他
So why don't you tell me how to find him again?
得了吧
Oh, come on.
告诉我他在哪儿
Tell me where he is.
他无处不在
He's everywhere.
无处不在
Everywhere!
他堂而皇之地坐在你书桌前
He's sitting at your desk,
他吻着你的女人 还和你家人淡定地共进晚餐
he's kissing your lover, he's eating supper with your family!
你是在掩护某个人吧？
You're protecting someone.
是你夫人吗？
Your wife.
她很久之前就不在了
She left long ago.
那是你的儿子？
Your son?
还是你女儿？
Your daughter.
你找不到她的
You won't find her.
她相当聪明
She's clever.
她比我聪明 知道怎么躲起来
She's smarter than me. She knows how to hide.
说出那人在哪 我就能保护你女儿
I can protect her if you tell me where he is.
我能保住她的命
I can keep her alive.
好啊
Yeah.
我向你承诺
You have my word.
你向我承诺？
Your word?
一个杀手也能信？
The word of an assassin!
说到做到
That's my word.
美国人
L'Américain.
你只要能救她
You save her,
她就能带你去 美国人 那儿 她非常了解
she can lead you to L'Américain. She knows L'Américain.
先去霍夫勒诊所看看
Try the Hoffler Klinik.
你现在就是只风筝 在飓风中飞舞的风筝 邦德先生
You're a kite dancing in a hurricane, Mr. Bond.
永别了
Solong.
你可真行 能让政府财政出钱为这个吐血买单
I can't deny I'm impressed you got H.M.G. to cough up for all this.
得了 政府哪有钱盖这种大楼啊
Good God, the government couldn't afford this kind of facility.
大部分还得靠私营企业的捐助
No, it was benefactors mostly, from the private sector.
当正式运行了
When it goes online,
这栋楼将成为史上最强悍的
this building will be the most sophisticated
数据收集系统
data gathering system in history.
成为全天候主宰世界的数字幽灵
The world's digital ghost, available 24/7.
也是乔治·奥威尔的终极噩梦
George Orwell's worst nightmare.
你喜欢就好
I'm glad you like it.
九只眼未获全票通过真是遗憾
My commiserations on losing the Nine Eyes vote.
对你打击挺大吧
Must have been a blow.
倒没什么 南非方面想通也只是个时间问题
Not really. Only a matter of time before the South Africans see the light.
而且罗马也不是一天建成的
And you know what they say, Rome wasn't built in a day.
可能用了一天半呢
Day and a half maybe.
我说麦克斯 我知道监控这事是日常必备
Look, Max, I know surveillance is a fact of life.
但让我担心的是你使用情报的方式
It's how you use the information that concerns me,
以及谁会用这些情报
and who is using it.
这是保障公众安全所必须的
This is what we need to do to keep the people safe.
00项目已经过时了
Double-0 program is prehistoric.
现在你还能单靠一个特工
Come on, M. You can't really tell me that one man in the field
就包打天下吗？
can compete with all of this,
有杀人执照也力不从心啊
running around out there with his license to kill.
你有没有真正杀过人 麦克斯？
Have you ever had to kill a man, Max?
有吗？
Have you?
要心里有底 你才可以扣动扳机
To pull that trigger, you have to be sure.
是的 先要进行调查 要分析评估 锁定目标
Yes, you investigate, analyze, assess, target.
然后你要盯着对方的眼睛
And then you have to look him in the eye.
接着做出判断
And you make the call.
那些个无人机 窃听器 摄像头 速记
And all the drones, bugs, cameras, transcripts,
以及所有现行的监控手段
all the surveillance in the world
都不会告诉你下一步怎么办
can't tell you what to do next.
一张杀人执照
A license to kill
也是一张不乱杀人的执照
is also a license not to kill.
我这么做也是被迫的
I didn't want to have to do this,
你好像已经控制不了你的特工了
but it looks like you still can't control your agents.
邦德 我帮你查过了
Bond? I ran that check.
貌似是位你曾经交过手的人 量子危机那次
Looks like you've had dealings with him before. Quantum.
果不其然 是怀特先生
Of course. Mr. White!
最近一次现身 是在奥地利的奥尔陶斯
Last unconfirmed sighting, Altaussee in Austria.
我再报个名字行吗？
Run another name, will you?
所以实施全面监控看来并非无稽之谈
So maybe there's something to be said for total surveillance after all.
你们监控军情六处的探员
You watch MI6 agents?
我们谁都监控
We watch everyone.
您先请坐
Please, take a seat.
我这边很快就完了
I'll be with you in just a moment.
在周一进行了测试之后
诊断出这位患者患有创伤后应激障碍
开了药 进行大强度的认知行为治疗
以颅骶疗法来辅助
请多包涵 邦德先生
Please excuse me, Mr. Bond.
我是玛德琳·斯旺医生
My name is Dr. Madeleine Swann.
我们今天的任务是分析你的需求
Ourjob today is to analyze your needs,
包括心理和身体两个层面
both psychological and physical.
真是开门见山啊
Hmm, sounds pretty straightforward.
希望您别介意 这景色容易让人分心
I hope you don't mind. The view can be distracting.
我还没注意到呢
I hadn't noticed.
您已经填了大部分的材料
I see you filled out most of the paperwork.
可以的话想问一下剩余的几个问题以完成评估
Just a few questions to complete your evaluation, ifl may.
你平时锻炼吗？
Do you exercise?
必要时才炼
When I have to.
你觉得工作给你带来的压力大吗？
Do you consider your employment to be psychologically stressful?
有时候觉得
Sometimes.
一般会喝多少酒？
How much alcohol do you consume?
过量
Too much.
我的问题再放宽点
Some broader questions.
小时候 你跟你的父母很亲近吗？
As a child, would you say you were close to your parents?
我从小父母就去世了
My parents died when I was young.
当时几岁？
Really? How old?
反正能记事了
Old enough to remember.
能问问怎么死的吗？
How, ifl may ask?
爬山时发生了意外
It was a climbing accident.
谁把你抚养成人的？
So who brought you up?
是别的人
Someone else.
我能问问吗？
Humor me.
一位就读过牛津和索邦两所名校 当上顾问
How does one train at Oxford and the Sorbonne become a consultant,
在无国界医生组织工作两年的人
spend two years with Médecins Sans Frontiéres
怎么会来到这荒山野岭的地方？
and end up here?
请恕我冒昧 人家很容易会认为
Forgive me, but anyone might think
你是在有所回避
you were hiding from something.
您来这儿可是花了不少钱的 邦德先生
You're paying a lot of money to be here, Mr. Bond.
到底是我问你啊 还是你问我？
Who's asking the questions, you or me?
当然你问了 请继续
Of course. Carry on.
这最后一问你是空着的
I see you left this final question blank.
你做什么职业？
What is your occupation?
这个要是填在表上恐怕会不太好看
Well, that's not the sort of thing that looks good on a form.
为什么呢？
And why is that?
我的工作是杀人
I kill people.
这世界多小
Small world?
他人在哪里？
Where is he?
你父亲去世了
Your father's dead.
两天前的事
Two days ago.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know?
因为我就在现场
Because I was there.
你杀了他？
Did you kill him?
我没那必要
I didn't have to.
他是自杀的
He did it himself.
大老远来就为了告诉我这个？
And you came all the way just to tell me this?
告诉我父亲已经死了？
That my father's dead?
我想说的是你生命有危险 而且我需要你帮助
I came to tell you that your life is in danger and I need your help.
- 为什么？- 我和他有过约定 要保护你
- Why? - I made a deal with him to protect you.
你在撒谎
You're lying.
他凭什么相信你？
Why would he trust you?
因为他也知道我有求于你们
Because he knew that I needed something in return.
你想干什么？
And what was that?
帮我找到 美国人
To find L'Américain.
询问结束了
This interview is over.
斯旺医生
Dr. Swann...
给你你10分钟离开这里 然后我会呼叫保安
You have 10 minutes to leave the building. Then I'm calling security.
谢谢你 斯旺医生
Thank you, Dr. Swann.
想来点什么吗 先生？
Can I get you something, sir?
伏特加马提尼 摇 但别搅拌
Vodka martini. Shaken, not stirred.
很抱歉告诉您 我们不提供酒水
I'm sorry, we don't serve alcohol.
我真是越来越喜欢这儿了
I'm really starting to love this place.
给他来一杯含消化酶的奶昔
He'll have the prolytic digestive enzyme shake.
没问题
Certainly.
你要是来取车
If you've come for the car,
车已经沉到台伯河底去了
I parked it at the bottom of the Tiber.
别担心 007 那只是辆价值三百万英镑的概念车
Well, not to worry, 007. lt was only a £3,000,000 prototype.
你怎么来了 Q？
Why are you here, Q?
我就是纯粹想休息一下而已
Oh, I just fancied a break, to be honest.
最近工作压力有点大
I've been a tad stressed at work recently.
军情五处整天盯着我们
What with C's people crawling all over us
M也想把我挂在圣诞树上当装饰品
and the fact that M wants my balls for Christmas decorations.
- 说重点 - 007 重点就是
- Get to the point. - The point, 007,
弗朗兹·奥伯豪斯不仅死了
is that Franz Oberhauser is dead.
棺材都下葬了
Dead and buried.
除非你现在就跟我回去
And unless you come back with me right now,
不然我和莫尼彭尼都前途不保
my career and Moneypenny's will go the same way.
你明白吗 现在事态已经全面失控了 你要是不
Do you understand? All hell is breaking loose out there and...
我看见他了 那是你的臆想
I saw him. You thought you saw him.
我们查阅了所有记录
We've been through the records.
20年前他和他父亲死于一场雪崩
He died in an avalanche with his father 20 years ago.
是 这些我都知道
Yes. I know that.
但我的确又见到他了
But I saw him.
我是不可能忘记他的
He's not someone I'll ever forget.
这么说 你有什么头绪吗？
So you have a lead?
有这么个名字 美国人
I have a name. L'Américain.
这就能缩小范围了吗？
Well, that narrows it down.
对不起 007 先说到这儿吧
Look, I'm sorry, 007, but time's up.
我的前途现在悬于一线了
My whole career is on the line here.
要么你现在回去走正常的渠道办事
Either you come back in and do this through proper channels,
要么我直接向M报告
or I go directly to M.
再帮我办件事吧 然后就没你事了
Do one more thing for me. Then you're out.
查查这东西的来头
Find out what you can from this.
我现在真是恨死你了
I really, really hate you right now.
谢了 Q
Thank you, Q.
- 先生 行了吗？- 请稍等
- Monsieur? Now? - Please?
你住哪啊？
Where are you staying?
佩夫斯纳旅馆 12号房
The Pevsner. Room 12.
一小时后见
One hour.
您的饮料 先生 一杯热解消化酶奶昔
Here you are, sir. One prolytic digestive enzyme shake.
能帮我个忙吗
Do me a favor, will you?
把这玩意倒厕所里
Throw that down the toilet.
中间环节都省了
Cut out the middleman.
你待着别动
No! Stay.
你们想要什么？
What do you want?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
你们都是哑巴吗？
Can't any of you speak?
顶住
Come on!
啊 别碰我
Argh, don't touch me!
嘿
Hey!
你应该先好好喘口气 冷静一下情绪
You need to take a breath and calm down.
你是受惊吓了
You're in shock.
离我远点 给我走开行不行
Get away from me! Just get away!
你不觉得是你把他们引来的吗
Did it cross your mind that you led them to me?
我现在没时间解释
I haven't got time for this.
你必须告诉我和 美国人 有关的一切细节
You need to tell me everything you know about L'Américain.
见鬼去吧
Go to hell!
我向你父亲保证过
I gave your father my word!
我凭什么相信你 就因为我父亲信任你吗？
And why should I trust you? Because my father did?
因为此时此刻 斯旺医生
Because right now, Dr. Swann,
我是你活下去的唯一机会
I'm your best chance of staying alive.
斯旺医生 这位是Q
Dr. Swann, Q.
Q 这位是斯旺医生
Q, Dr. Swann.
- 你好 - 幸会幸会
- Hello. - Enchanted.
邦德 我们俩先谈 不带她
Bond, we need to talk. Alone.
她都知道
She knows.
- 可是 邦德 - 她已经知道了
- But, Bond... - She knows.
你查到了什么？
What have you got?
我得向你道歉 007
I owe you an apology, 007.
你这回中大奖了
You are onto something.
奥伯豪斯确实还没死 这戒指就是证明
Oberhauser is still alive. The ring proves it.
我搜遍了近五年的工作记录 他们都指向同一个组织
And it seems they were all part of one organization.
拉契夫 量子项目 斯奇亚拉 你的朋友 席尔瓦先生
Le Chiffre, Quantum, Sciarra, your friend Mr. Silva.
你知道他们都和谁有关联吗？
And do you know who links them all?
是他
Him.
没错就是他
Exactly.
这个神秘组织 知道它叫什么名字吗？
This organization, do you know what it's called?
- 不知道 - 幽灵党
- No. - Spectre.
它的名字叫 幽灵党
Its name is Spectre.
她怎么会知道？
How does she know that?
因为我父亲就是组织成员
Because my father was part of it.
那么 你应该看看这个
Then I think that you ought to see this.
现在切换到南非现场传来的画面
You're looking at pictures from South Africa right now
我们能看到的是
of what appears to be a huge explosion.
Q 马上回伦敦去
Q, go back to London.
M需要你的帮助 然后继续追踪我
M's gonna need your help. And keep tracking me.
我会的
I will.
对了 邦德 你一定要找到 美国人
And, Bond, you have to find L'Américain.
他是找到奥伯豪斯的唯一线索
He's our only link to Oberhauser.
美国人
It's not a person.
不是一个人 那是一个地点
It's a place.
(摩洛哥 吉尔丹)
谢谢
Thank you.
他俩就在这儿过的新婚之夜
This is where they spent their wedding night.
然后每年都会回来一次
They came back every year.
后来又带着我一起来
Then they brought me with them, too.
即使后来都离婚了 父亲一个人还来
He kept coming back, even after the divorce.
那我觉得 太遗憾了
Well, then I'm sorry.
为什么？
What for?
这是什么？
SWANNI What is it?
属于你的遗产
It's your inheritance.
- 不来点吗？- 不了 谢谢
- Want some? - No, thank you.
错过了好事别赖我啊
You don't know what you're missing.
不可能就这么点吧
This can't be it.
算了 先敬你爸一杯
Well, here's to your father.
我答应过我自己 绝不让自己再受到那个男人的伤害
I promised myself I would never be hurt by that man again.
跟他断了一切联系
I cut off all contact.
我再也不想跟他和他的生活有任何关系
I didn't want anything to do with him or his sick life.
而他就在断气之前
And then, with his dying breath
却让你来找我
he sends me you.
真讽刺啊 不是吗？
Ironic, no?
你不该对他这么狠
You shouldn't be so hard on him.
他本来早几周前就要死的
The man ljust met should have been dead weeks ago.
硬撑着没咽气就是为了你啊
The only reason his heart was still beating was you.
我会抽时间去看我的父亲 邦德先生
I'll mourn my father in my own time, Mr. Bond.
现在我要去睡觉了
And, now, I'm going to bed.
休想有一丝邪念
Don't think for one moment
你以为我会因为父亲死了 就会对你投怀送抱
Don't think for one moment this is where I fall into your arms,
寻求精神慰藉吗？
seeking solace for my dead daddy.
你给我坐那儿
You sit there.
好好站岗 那是你最擅长的了
Keep watch. That's what you're good at.
你胆敢靠近我一步 我就杀了你
Come anywhere near me and I'll kill you.
这我毫不怀疑
I don't doubt it.
快看 那儿有两个你
Look. There are two of you.
有两个詹姆斯
Two Jameses.
我可真幸运
Lucky me.
我在这里做什么
What am I doing here?
致骗子
To liars...
和杀手
...and killers.
致骗子
To liars...
和杀手
...and killers...
他们无所不在
...everywhere.
谁派你来的？
Who sent you?
你在替谁卖命？
Who are you working for?
你到底躲哪儿了？
Now, where did you go?
果然
Of course.
(与维丝帕·林德对谈)
那是什么？
What is it?
没什么
Nothing.
这是什么？
What's this?
这些是坐标
It's coordinates.
你父亲当时在扫描某个卫星电话
Your father was scanning for a particular satellite phone.
他在找某个人
He was looking for someone.
他找的是这个人
He was looking for him.
他是让我来完成他的工作
And he sent me here to finish the job.
- 我要跟你一起去 - 不 你别去
- I'm coming with you. - No, you're not.
我要你活下去
I like you alive.
我能照顾好自己
I can look after myself.
这个并不是重点
That's beside the point.
我可能有去无回
I might not be coming back.
我知道
I know.
但我想知道我父亲究竟遭遇了什么
But I want to understand what happened to my father.
说吧 他是去什么地方？
So, where was he going?
不毛之地
No where.
这是怎么回事
What's going on?
会议提前了 你没收到信息吗？
The meeting was brought forward. Did you not get the message?
根本就没收到
No, we didn't.
这是史上最短的会了
Shortest meeting I can remember.
难道南非也同意了？
South Africans on board, I take it?
对 是啊 他们也只能如此了
Yeah, well, who can blame them?
九只眼协议现在正式生效了
Nine Eyes is now officially sanctioned.
新系统72小时内就启动
The new system goes live in less than 72 hours.
这可是向前了一大步
It's a major step forward.
全球性的情报合作将改变一切
Global intelligence cooperation changes everything.
你之前说过了
As you said before.
听着
Look.
他们让我来领导这个委员会
They've asked me to head the new committee.
当然 然后呢？
Yes? And?
我得跟你说 我已经跟内政大臣谈过了
And I should tell you I've spoken with the Home Secretary.
鉴于我给他的新信息
And in light of the new information I've given him,
他决定立即停止00特工计划
he's decided to close down the double-0 program with immediate effect.
你知道你在做什么吗？
You don't know what you're doing.
不是针对你个人的
It's not personal.
那是未来所在
It's the future.
而你
And...
你已经过时了
You're not.
你丫不要太狂啊
You're a cocky little bastard, aren't you?
我就当你在夸我
I'll take that as a compliment.
想得美
I wouldn't.
这事儿还没完呢
This isn't over yet.
帮我熨下好吗？
Would you press this for me?
- 好的 先生 - 谢谢
- Yes, sir. - Thank you.
拿起来
Pick it up.
我讨厌枪
I hate guns.
我答应过你爸要保护你的
I promised him I'd protect you.
所以第一件事就是教你保护自己
The first thing to do is to teach you how to protect yourself.
我要是误伤了你怎么办？
What if I shoot you by mistake?
误伤又不是第一次了
Wouldn't be the first time.
拿起来
Pick it up.
我说了 我讨厌枪
I said, I hate guns.
这是西格226
SIG 226.
前准星 后瞄准器 击锤
Front sight. Rear sight. Hammer.
你只需要瞄准 扣动扳机
You just point it. You squeeze the trigger.
尽量不要闭眼
You try not to close your eyes.
听我的 试试吧
Please, try it.
看来你已经无师自通了啊
I don't have to teach you anything, do I?
曾经有个男的来我家要杀我父亲
A man once came to our house to kill my father.
可他不知道我就在楼上卧室里玩儿
He didn't know I was upstairs playing in my bedroom.
也不知道我爸在水池下
Or that Papa kept a Beretta Nine-millimeter
藏了一把9毫米的伯莱塔
under the sink with the bleach.
所以我特别痛恨枪
That's why I hate guns.
看来也能跳过徒手格斗教学了
I think we'll skip hand-to-hand combat.
晚上好 长官
Good evening, sir.
抱歉打断您的晚餐 我们刚收到新消息
Sorry to interrupt yoursuppen but we have some news.
晚上好长官
Evening, sir.
通过使用 智能血液 我们已经追踪到了邦德
Using the Smart Blood, I've tracked Bond
他人在北非
to a point here in North Africa.
现在所有地图都指向那片沙漠
See, every known map registers it as empty desert.
没错 但您看这儿
Exactly. But if you look
卫星放大图像却能看到这个
at the satellite blowup, you can clearly see this.
我们帮不了他
We can't help him.
但我们知道他要去哪儿
But, sir, we know where he's heading.
C正监视我们的一举一动
C is watching everything we do.
这么做只会给他白送情报
We're only handing them more information.
长官 我们不能这样抛弃邦德
Sir, we can't just desert Bond.
无能为力 他只能被削弱
We have to. We only make him weaker.
可我们知道他在哪儿啊
But, sir, we know exactly where he is.
这我明白 我们能追踪他 别人也一样可以
Yes, I know, but ifwe can track him, so can others.
给我删除所有 智能血液 相关文件
Delete all the Smart Blood files.
要不留痕迹
Everything.
他只有靠自己了
He's on his own.
盯着多不合适啊
You shouldn't stare.
天啊 这是同一个人吗
Well, you shouldn't look like that.
帮你点杯开胃酒吧
May I get you an apéritif?
还没想好呢
I'm not sure.
我喝酒可会惹麻烦 会让我做出格的事
It gets me into trouble. Makes me do crazy things.
那样可不行啊
Well, we can't have that.
所以我就来伏特加马提尼 加点刺激
So, I'll have a vodka martini, dirty.
我也来那个
Make that two.
我有个问题
I have a question.
什么问题？
Well, what's that?
为什么有那么多职业可供选择
Why, given every other possible option,
偏有人要当职业杀手呢？
does a man choosethelfie of a paid assassin?
不当杀手 当牧师怎么样？
Well, it was that or the priesthood.
我可是认真的 这就是你想要的吗？
I'm serious. Is this really what you want?
整天躲在阴影之中
Living in the shadows?
追杀别人
Hunting?
或被别人追杀
Being hunted?
背后总有人盯着你 一直是孤独一人
Always looking behind you? Always alone?
可我并不孤独
But I'm not alone.
你先回答我的问题
Answer the question.
我不知道自己是否有得可选
I'm not sure I ever had a choice.
但我也不会专门想这个问题
Anyway, I don't stop to think about it.
你如果想了会怎样？
What would happen if you did?
- 专门去想吗？- 是的
- Stop? - Yes.
我不知道
I don't know.
这是您的酒 先生
Your drinks, sir.
请先放那里吧
Could you leave them there, please.
知道吗 我觉得你错了
You know, I think you're wrong.
我错了吗？
I am?
每个人都会有选择
We always have a choice.
就为这个干一杯
I'll drink to that.
该死
Shit.
现在该干什么
What do we do now?
这样估计要等很久
This might be a long wait.
你要不要重新考虑下？
Are you having second thoughts?
为时已晚了
Too late now.
那是什么？
What's that?
那车 可是1948年产的劳斯莱斯银魅
That is a 1948 Rolls-Royce Silver Wraith.
请上车
Please.
我很害怕 詹姆斯
I'm scared, James.
下午好 邦德先生 斯旺医生
Good afternoon, Mr. Bond, Dr. Swann.
终于能见到你们 我们都深感荣幸
I want you to knowjust how excited we all are to finally meet you.
我们也很高兴能来
Well, it's a pleasure to be here.
主人想请你们先休息放松一下
Your host invites you both to rest,
四点的时候会请你们喝一杯
relax, and join him for drinks at 4:00.
- 转告你主人 我们会准时到 - 好极了
- Tell our host we won't be late. - Wonderful.
带你们去房间前 还有一件事情
Before we show you to your rooms, just one more thing.
你可要小心点
You be careful with that.
它已经上膛了
Ifsloaded.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是个非常特别的地方
This is a very special place.
主人已要求我们 只能你们独自进去
He has requested you enter it alone.
没问题
Of course.
来杯香槟吗？
Champagne?
要不再等会儿？
Maybe later.
当然可以
Certainly.
我想我们该表现出惊叹的样子
I think we're meant to be impressed.
摸摸看
Touch it.
你想摸 但摸无妨
You can touch it ifyou want.
知道这是什么吗？
Do you know what it is?
这是块陨石
It's a meteorite.
是的 没错
Yes, exactly.
卡腾霍夫 人类已有的最古老陨石
The Kartenhoff. The oldest in human possession.
是它在地球上留下了这个陨石坑
The very meteorite which made this crater.
试想一下
Think about it.
先前那么多年里 它是那么孤独而寂静
So many years up there, alone, silent,
一直在积聚动能 最终在地球上留下印记
building momentum until it chose to make its mark on Earth.
它是股不可阻挡的巨大力量
A huge, unstoppable force.
但他最终还是停下来了 不是吗？
Except it did stop, didn't it?
停在了这儿
Right here.
你都不知道我期待这一刻有多久了
I can't tell you how much I've been looking forward to this.
我们所有人重聚在一起
All of us here, together.
一个小团圆
A reunion.
很高兴你也来了 亲爱的玛德琳
I'm so glad you came, too, dear Madeleine.
我第一次见到你时 你还是个小女孩
You were just a girl when I saw you first.
有次我去你家找你父亲
I came to your home once to see your father.
我不记得了
I don't remember that.
可我记得
Butldo.
请吧
Shall we?
这是什么地方？
What is this place?
和情报有关
Information.
情报就是一切
Information is all,
不是吗？
is it not?
比如说
For example,
你现在应该知道00计划已经寿终正寝了
you must know by now that the double-0 program is officially dead.
这让我不禁好奇你为何而来
Which leads me to speculate exactly why you came.
我说 詹姆斯 你为何而来？
So, James, why did you come?
我来这是为了杀了你
I came here to kill you.
而我认为你是来送死
And I thought you came here to die.
只是看问题的角度不同罢了
Well, it's all a matter of perspective.
既然说到看问题的角度
Speaking of perspective.
- 这是直播吗？- 实时画面 格林尼治时间十六点二十分
- Is this live? - Live and direct. 16:20 GMT.
真是无巧不成书啊
What an uncanny coincidence.
法语有一句谚语
The French have a saying,
"玻璃的宿命就是破碎"
"It's the fate of glass to break."
看来也许间谍的宿命 就是消失
Well, maybe it's the fate of spies to just disappear.
不过幸运的是
But with any luck,
我们有所成就
we leave something behind.
与此同时 C会继续出色领导大家的工作
In the meantime, l'm sure C will keep you all busy.
谢谢大家
Thank you all.
真是感人 你不觉得吗？
That's touching, don't you think?
可惜啊 詹姆斯
Well, James,
你成了被遗忘的角落
it looks like you're all alone.
你难道只是个偷窥狂吗？
Not much more than a voyeur, are you?
胆小到不敢加入我们
Too scared to join in.
看来你还没明白
I don't think you quite understand.
不 我很明白
Oh, I think I do.
你策划那几个城市的袭击 伤及无辜 就是逼人就范
You set cities on fire and watch innocent people burn,
让那些政府加入
so you can convince governments to join...
你操盘的情报网络
an intelligence network you've paid for.
整件事并不复杂
Not that complicated.
我猜我们的小朋友C 他该是你的门徒之一吧
I'm guessing our little friend, C, he's one of your disciples.
就算是吧
You could say that.
他会得到什么好处？
And what does he get out of it?
什么都没有
Nothing.
他和我都能看得很远
He's a visionary, like me.
看得远的人
Visionaries.
精神病院里多的是
Psychiatric wards are full of them.
而你连眼前都看不清
Whereas you couldn't see what's right in front of you.
我们交手那么多次 你却从来没发现过我
You came across me so many times and yet you never saw me.
拉契夫 格林 席尔瓦
Le Chiffre, Greene, Silva.
他们都死了
All dead.
没错
Yeah, that's right.
你我之间有种模式
A nice pattern developed.
你侵犯我的世界 我就毁掉你的世界
You interfered in my world, I destroyed yours.
你觉得你生命中
Or did you think it was coincidence
所有女人最后都死了是种巧合吗？
that all the women in your life ended up dead?
就拿维斯帕·林德来说
Vesper Lynd, for example.
这位算是举足轻重的吧 他没跟你说起过吗？
She was the big one. Has he told you about her?
当然还有这位 你最亲爱的M夫人
And then, of course, your beloved M.
也永远离开了你
Gone forever.
是我
Me.
全都是我干的 詹姆斯
Itwas all me, James.
这些都源于我 你所有痛苦都是我写就的
It's always been me. The author of all your pain.
你是个勇敢的女人 亲爱的
You're a brave woman, my dear.
我终于明白我父亲为什么会疯了
Now I understand why my father lost his mind.
他没有疯 他就是软弱
He didn't lose his mind, he wasjustweak.
但他起码知道他是在与谁为敌
But at least he understood what he was up against.
他们不能理解的一个残酷事实是
You see, they failed to comprehend the crucial fact,
一个可怕的事件也会催生完美的事物
that a terrible event canleadto something wonderful.
既然说到你父亲 不妨让你也看看
Since you mention your father, I'll show you.
她相当聪明 她比我聪明
She's clever. She's smarter than me.
知道怎么躲起来
She knows how to hide.
我就能保护你女儿 说出那人在哪
I can protect her if you tell me where he is.
我能保住她的命
I can keep her alive.
好啊
Yeah.
我向你承诺
You have my word.
不不不 快关掉
No, no, no. Turn this off.
你向我承诺？
Your word?
一个杀手也能信？
The word of an assassin!
马上给我关掉
Turn this off.
- 这一段很重要 - 我说了马上关掉
- This is important. - I said turn it off!
我想让你明白一件事
I want you to understand something.
说到做到
That's my word.
玛德琳
Madeleine?
看着我
Look at me.
别看他 玛德琳 看着我
Don't look at him, Madeleine. Look at me.
美国人
L'Américain.
你只要能救她
You save her,
她就能带你去 美国人 那儿 她非常了解
she can lead you to L'Américain. She knows L'Américain.
先去霍夫勒诊所看看
Try the Hoff/er Klinik.
你现在就是只风筝 在飓风中飞舞的风筝 邦德先生
You're a kite dancing in a hurricane, Mr. Bond.
永别了
So long.
那些能把人聚到一起的事情
The things that bring people together.
也许是恐惧 也许是美
Out of horror, beauty.
肉体折磨太简单了 流于肤浅
Torture is easy, on a superficial level.
一个人可以看着自己被开膛
A man can watch himself being disemboweled
从中会产生出巨大恐惧
and derive great horror from the experience,
但这种折磨远未触及其灵魂
but it's still going on at a distance.
仍没有触及到他的真正内心
It isn't taking place where he is.
你应该很清楚 亲爱的玛德琳
As you know all too well, dear Madeleine,
真正的他存在于他的大脑之中
a man lives inside his head.
那里才安放着他的灵魂
That's where the seat of his soul is.
最近我和詹姆斯同时
Now, James and lwere both present recently
目睹一个人刚被挖去双眼
when a man was deprived of his eyes.
接着一件最令人震惊的事情发生了
And the most astonishing thing happened.
你注意到了吗？
Didn't you notice?
他的灵魂已经不在了
He wasn't there anymore.
他虽然还活着 可灵魂已死
He'd gone even though he was still alive.
就在生与死的那一瞬间
So in this brief moment between life and death,
他脑海里再没有任何人
there was nobody inside his skull.
真是奇妙
Most odd.
那么 詹姆斯
So, James.
我现在要
I'm going to penetrate
渗透进你的大脑
to where you are.
去触及你的灵魂所在 探索你的脑部世界
To the inside ofyourhead.
这第一根探针会玩弄你的视觉
Now, the first probe will play with your sight,
你的听觉
your hearing
还有平衡感
and your balance,
只需要最轻微的操作即可
just with the subtlest of manipulations.
那你就尽管来吧
Well, get on with it then.
没什么能比听你啰嗦更痛苦了
Nothing can be as painful as listening to you talk.
那好吧
All right.
我们开始
Let's begin.
你为什么要这么做？
Why are you doing this?
你应该知道 詹姆斯很小的时候
You probably know that James here
就失去了双亲
lost his parents when he was young.
但你知道吗 后来是我父亲
But did you know that it was my father
陪他度过最艰难的时光
who helped him through this difficult time?
一连两个冬天
Over the course of two winters
我父亲教他滑雪 教他登山 还有打猎
he taught him to ski, and climb, and hunt.
他为这位蓝眼珠的可怜孤儿抚平了心灵创伤
He soothed the wounds of the poor little blue-eyed orphan.
还让我把他当做自己的兄弟
Asked me to treat him as a brother.
把他当做小弟弟看
My little brother.
我们之间结下了深厚情谊
They formed quite an attachment.
所以
So,
你选择把他杀了
you killed him.
没错 那是我干的
Yes, i did.
你们应该能猜到 布谷鸟为了在别的鸟巢产卵会怎么做
You know what happens when a cuckoo hatches inside another bird's nest?
我知道
Yes.
它会把别的蛋推出巢外
It forces the other eggs out.
没错
Yes.
所以 这只布谷鸟让我意识到我的父亲必须死
Well, this cuckoo made me realize my father's life had to end.
可以说 我的所作所为是他逼的
In a way, he's responsible for the path I took.
所以谢谢你 布谷
So, thank you. Cuckoo.
能来点别的鸟叫吗？弗朗兹
Do you know any other birdcalls, Franz?
你好 猫咪
Hello, pussy.
弗朗兹·奥伯豪斯20年前就死了
Franz Oberhauser died 20 years ago, James.
他跟他父亲 同时死于一场雪崩
In an avalanche, alongside his father.
现在跟你说话的人 你脑子里想的这个人
The man you are talking to now, the man inside your head,
叫恩内斯特·史戴弗·布鲁夫尔德
is Ernst Stavro Blofeld.
大有来头？
Catchy name.
承袭自我母亲家族那边
My mother's bloodline.
探针要是在脑内梭状回里扎对了地方
If the needle finds the correct spot in the fusiform gyrus,
你就谁也不认识了
you'll recognize no one.
当然 你那些女人的脸
Of course, the faces of your women
互相换来换去也无妨 詹姆斯
are interchangeable, aren't they, James?
你会连她都不认识的
You won't know who she is.
她只是你前往坟墓途中 看到的一张脸而已
Just another passing face on your way to the grave.
他临死的时候会根本认不出你
He dies not knowing who you are.
一个杀手的女儿
The daughter of an assassin.
唯一能真正理解他的人
The only one who could have understood him.
可惜了
Shame.
我爱你
I love you.
那对蓝眼珠还认得出你吗？
Do those blue eyes still recognize you?
到哪儿我都能认出你
I'd recognize you anywhere.
我的手表
The watch.
1分钟之后
One minute.
只剩1分钟
他说什么了吗？
Did he say something?
光阴似箭
Tempus fugit.
- 什么？- 光阴 似箭
- What? - Tempus fugit.
听不见 詹姆斯
I can't hear you, James.
我说
I said,
真是时光飞逝啊
doesn't time fly?
去那边
In there!
我们该回家了
Let's go home.
这事儿还没完呢
It's not over yet.
我没听说过希尔德布兰德
I've never even heard of Hildebrand.
这样才叫安全堡垒啊
That is the general idea with safe houses.
这里能有多安全？
Exactly how safe is this, sir?
很快就能知道了
We're about to find out.
果然安全
It's safe.
你们在这等着
Better wait here.
我是M
I'm M.
玛德琳·斯旺
Madeleine Swann.
很高兴见到你
Pleased to meet you.
007 你有什么新消息？
So, what do you have for me, 007?
最近死亡的幽灵党头目 恩内斯特·史戴弗·布鲁夫尔德
The recently deceased head of Spectre, Ernst Stavro Blofeld,
以及他的情报部长 你的新搭档C
and his chief of intelligence, your new best friend, C.
马上就要接管他在我们眼皮子底下建的
About to take control of his very own global surveillance system
那个强大的全球监控体系了
that he built right here under our noses.
那最好抓紧时间 系统午夜就要启动了
Then we'd better move. The system goes online at midnight.
他们要是得逞 幽灵党就会掌控一切
If that happens, Spectre will have control of everything.
你和我去会一会C
So, you and I will have a quiet word with C
同时Q侵入系统 组织系统上线
while Q hacks into the system and stops it going online.
那可不容易
It won't be easy.
他会有办法的 他一向如此
He'll find a way. He always does.
欢迎你归队 007
It's good to have you back, 007.
长官
Sir.
詹姆斯 我办不到
James, I can't.
我会回来找你的 等这一切结束之后
I'll come back for you when it's all over.
不 我做不到
No, I can't.
你是不能待在这儿 还是
No, you can't stay here, or you...
我不能再过这种生活
I can't go back to this life.
我也不想让你做出改变
And I'm not going to ask you to change.
你就是这种人
This is who you are.
你是要跟我告别？
You're saying good-bye.
是的
Yes.
你保重
Take care.
你是个好人 詹姆斯
You're a good man, James.
黑进去了吗 Q？
Are you in yet, Q?
还有好几层难搞的防火墙
A few layers of impenetrable security still to go,
但我应该是有些进展了
but I think I 'm getting somewhere.
- 他们看见我们了 - 倒车
- They've seen us! - Reverse!
走
Go!
把他带进楼去
Get him in the building!
快走啊 走啊
Move. Move!
快回去找到M 马上 两个都要抓到
Go back and find M, now! We need them both.
被人监视的感觉不好吧
Not a good feeling being watched, is it?
别告诉我这是你捣的鬼
Don't tell me you're responsible for this.
哪有 是我的军需官Q
No, but my Quartermaster is.
他可不是一般的才华横溢
And he's extremely talented.
做得漂亮
Well, bravo.
可你们没有意识到 你们已经被炒了
But in case you hadn't realized it, you two are out of a job.
所以 你现在算是非法闯入
So you're trespassing.
恐怕是你错判局势了 麦克斯
I'm afraid you've got the wrong end of the stick, Max.
我们要阻止系统上线
We're going to stop this system going online.
还要把你也送进去
And then I'm going to bring you in.
未免无凭无据吧
On what grounds exactly?
就凭你交友不慎
Poor taste in friends.
放眼看看这个世界
Take a look at the world.
一片混乱
Chaos.
因为有像你这样的人
Because people like you,
层层官僚和政客们
paper-pushers and politicians,
才会毫无担当 终日无所作为
are too spineless to do what needs to be done.
所以我跟其他人结成联盟 要让权力能物尽其用
So I made an alliance to put the power where it should be.
现在你们打着民主政治的旗号 想让它胎死腹中
And now you want to throw it away for the sake of "democracy."
这是何等荒唐
Whatever the hell that is.
令人费解 愚钝之极
How predictably moronic.
但这不就是M毕生的使命吗？
But then isn't that what M stands for?
愚蠢
"Moron."
那我们现在也清楚C先生的使命了
And now we know what C stands for.
太大意了
"Careless."
拜托
Come on.
不 不 不
No,no,no!
你还真是一只不死鸟啊
You're a hard man to kill, Blofeld.
但愿没让你疼得太厉害
I do hope that doesn't hurt too much.
我的伤口会愈合的
My wounds will heal.
可你的伤口呢？
What about yours?
看看四周吧 詹姆斯
Look around you, James. Look.
你的世界就剩下这些
This is what's left of your world.
你所代表的一切 你所信仰的一切 都化作乌有
Everything you ever stood for, everything you believed in, a ruin.
我们干嘛在这儿？
Why are we here?
你想我了？
Did you miss me?
并没有
No.
但我知道有人想你了
But I know someone who does.
她人在哪儿？
Where is she?
那得靠你去找了
That's for you to find out.
三分钟后 这座大楼会被夷为平地
In three minutes, this building will be demolished.
我轻易就能离开
I can get out easily.
而你得做出抉择
Now, you have a choice.
是豁出命去救她
Die trying to save her or
还是 自己保命活在痛苦之中
save yourself and live with the pain.
你在虚张声势
You're bluffing.
我有吗？
Am I?
我让你左右为难了吧？
I've really put you through it, haven't I?
谁让我是你兄弟呢？
That's brothers for you.
太了解如何操纵你了
They always know which buttons to press.
玛德琳
Madeleine!
拜托
Come on.
好的
Yes!
走吧
Let's go.
你先请
After you.
为什么不正视现实 M？
Why can't you just face it, M?
你没有存在价值了
You don't matter anymore.
我也许是没有
Maybe I don't.
但有些必须有
But something has to.
死了
Dead.
- 有邦德的消息吗？- 没有
- Any word on Bond? - No.
但我可以猜得到
But I can hazard a guess.
玛德琳
Madeleine!
你相信我吗？
Do you trust me?
我还有选择吗？
Do I have a choice?
想都别想
Not anymore.
快点儿
Come on!
别了 詹姆·斯邦德
Good-bye, James Bond.
先生 这里是管制区域
Sir, this is a terrorist alert.
马洛里 00计划部的
Mallory, double-0 section.
解除戒备
Stand them down.
E组 都别开火
Echo team, hold fire.
解除戒备
Stand down.
了结了吧
Finish it.
快了结了吧
没有子弹
Out of bullets.
而且现在
And besides,
我还有更重要的事情要办
I've got something better to do.
根据2001年的《特殊措施法案》
Under the Special Measures Act of 2001,
我代表英国政府正式拘捕你
lam detaining you on behalf of Her Majesty's Government.
邦德
Bond?
- 你来这儿做什么？- 早安 Q
- What are you doing here? - Good morning, Q.
我以为你走了呢
I thought you'd gone.
是啊
I have.
但我还缺一样东西
There's just one thing I need.